# Dawn Sheedy (she/they)

Software Engineer with several years of experience specializing in web application development. I take pride in writing clean, documented, and reusable code. I love taking on challenges and working with individuals who are passionate about technology.

Seattle, WA https://dawnsheedy.com

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Clearwater Analytics, Seattle — L2 Software Development Engineer

July 2022 - Present

Quickly got up to speed and learned required technologies (Java Libraries, Angular). Led a training on Angular. Pushed for more thorough documentation for code and tickets. Wrote new and overhauled existing code to be modular, readable, and well-documented. Planned and initiated a common React component library for internal applications. Consistently provided accurate time estimates for tasks.

### Press Hook, Remote — Full-Stack Engineer

September 2021 - July 2022

Worked as a vital early developer in a fast-paced startup environment. Integral part of a transition to utilizing React for FE interfaces. Architected and implemented a custom real-time messaging system. Implemented CI/CD processes. Contributed to improving internal documentation. Screened and interviewed candidates. Assisted internal non-technical employees with issues.

### Kinstone, LLC, Remote — Volunteer Software Developer

August 2016 - February 2022

Worked with an international team of volunteers to provide an interactive, engaging experience for thousands of concurrent viewers. Utilized 3rd party APIs to deliver projects including a chat bot that integrated with other in-house systems. Provided rapid prototypes to prove concepts, including a live closed captioning utility.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Virginia Commonwealth University, Virginia — Computer Science

August 2019 - December 2021 (Incomplete due to reasons unrelated to performance)

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript/Typescript

- React & Redux
- Angular
- Node

HTML/CSS

Java

Python

SQL (MS, Postgres, etc.)

CI/CD (Jenkins, GHA, etc.)

System Architecture

Microservices

Testing

Docker

Git

#### **BUSINESS SKILLS**

Agile Process

Skill Acquisition/Self-teaching

Collaborating

Communication

Assisting/Training Others

Time Estimation/Planning

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Contract Work — Python (Django), Azure, React

Created a utility for creating and automatically scoring mental health assessments.

# Unity Jubeat Rewrite — Python (Django), Azure, React

Wrote my own version of the Japanese arcade game *Jubeat* using unity targeting the iPad. This was an exercise to learn Unity, improve my C# skills, and generally become more well rounded.

#### Personal Website — React/CSS

Used React, React-Router, HTML, and CSS to create a landing page that is distinct and related to my interests and aesthetics.

# DDRLights - C++, Arduino, Electronics

Forked Stepmania, an open source rhythm game, and modified it to generate automated light patterns based on stepfiles. Original version utilized stage lights controlled via the DMX protocol.

## Forza Telemetry Viewer - Go, React, Websockets

Created a user interface for displaying current vehicle information from Forza Horizon telemetry data. Intended for use as a stream overlay.

### Elite: Dangerous Alexa Control — Python, AWS

Wrote an Alexa skill for personal use that allowed voice control for many aspects of Elite: Dangerous. (e.g. "Alexa, tell ship to deploy landing gear" -> deploys landing gear in-game)

## Virtual Dance Pad — Python, Oculus SDK

Wrote a basic application that converted VR controller positions in defined spaces to key inputs. For the purpose of zip-tying controllers to my shoes and playing DDR.

### Collaborative Captioning App — Websockets, Node, React

Wrote a proof of concept application for aggregating captions written by multiple people and pushing them into a twitch livestream. Ended up being scrapped due to typing speed requiring stenographers.

### Sprinterface — Raspberry Pi, Node, HTML/CSS/JS

Wrote a basic interface for a family member for them to control the lights/other electronics in their Sprinter van using a tablet.